Lokendra Singh Chouhan

Application Security - SDE 2 @ Nutanix

With 8 Years of Industry experience into tools development, automation and security, an eye for innovation and my inquisitive nature, I aspire to be involved in work where I can utilize my skills creatively & effectively contribute towards organization's and my personal growth.

\times	lokendra91@gmail.com		+91 955 252 8557
0	Pune, India	in	linkedin.com/in/lokendra91
0	github.com/lokendra9009		

SKILLS

Automation Testing Python Web Security Testing Java Pytest BDD CI/CD Jenkins					
Automation Frameworks Application Security Penetration Testing ElasticSearch TestNG DevSecOps AWS					
Vulnerability Management Maven Gradle DAST/SAST Teaching Network Security Ethical Hacking C	CTF				
Perforce / Git Selenium Webdriver Autoit Cucumber					

WORK EXPERIENCE

Member Of Technical Staff SDE-2

Nutanix

02/2021 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop and maintain the tools for automated application security pipeline for Applications
- Setup up the CI build pipeline for Secure Software Development
- Security Scanner APIs Integration

Senior Security Automation Engineer

Nuance Communications

08/2020 - 02/2021

Achievements/Tasks

- Performed active and passive scans using Burp Suite and ZAP for application under test.
- Automated ZAP passive scan for the application under test.
- Automated dependency checks in order to ship more secure application with third party dependencies.
- Designed roadmap for "DevSecOps" for the application.
- Performed OWASP Top 10 security testing of web applications.
- Discovered security flaws like broken access control, brute force attack and improper DMARC record vulnerability.

Senior QA Engineer

Nuance Communication

03/2017 - 07/2020

Achievements/Tasks

- Building BDD Test Automation Framework using Cucumber Python and Java.
- Maintenance and Expansion of automated test cases in automation framework.
- Evaluation of various test automation framework. Doubled the test cases count keeping the execution time almost same.
- Continuous Integration of Test Framework using Jenkins.
- Written automated scripts for Image Comparison and Audio Comparison that saved 19 man hours per month.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Test Engineer Imagination Technologies

09/2015 - 03/2017

Achievements/Tasks

- Tested GPU drivers on Linux and NWS & Xorg windowing system.
- Executed 80-100% test plans including Unit Test, Performance test, Stability test.
- Created test cases, defect tracking, defect triaging.
- Prepared test execution script using python/shell to completely automated unit test execution.
- Created test delivered documentations & conducted training sessions for teams.

Software Test Engineer

Amdocs

07/2013 - 07/2015

Achievements/Tasks

- Executed End to End flows for Amdocs CRM. OMS & other retail frontends web application.
- Executed End to End Test scenarios involving Smoke testing, Regression testing, New Functionality testing.
- Reported, Managed & Triaged multiple severity 1 and 2 defects on daily basis.
- Interacted with BA team and other stakeholders for smooth delivery of application under test.
- Created scripts using Selenium Webdriver and Autoit for automating redundant jobs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science Acropolis Institute of Tech. & Research, Indore

08/2009 - 06/2013 Indore, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Automation Selenium Webdriver, Autoit, Sikuli, Page **Security Tools** Kali Linux, Burp Suite, ZAP, NMAP, Nikto,

Object Model, Cucumber, Pytest, Locust,

Anaconda, Jupyter Notebooks

Dependency Checker, Metasploit,
Microsoft Threat Modelling Tool, Social

Engineering Toolkit, Dirb, Hydra

Build Tools, Git, Maven, Chef Inspec, Jenkins, Gradle **Programming** Python, Java **CI/CD, Version** Languages

CI/CD, Version Control

CERTIFICATES

ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level (ITB0061996) Introduction to Python for Data Science - Microsoft

(4T2016) (Microsoft and edX)

Automate The Boring Stuff With Python Programming

DIPLOME D'ETUDES EN LANGUE FRANCAISE DELF A1

(UC-YM41OAOG) (French) (091755001704)

LANGUAGES

English French Hindi Marathi

Full Professional Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency Elementary Proficiency